<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fabian&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fabian&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Fabian&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Probing the origins of human acetylcholinesterase inhibition via QSAR modeling and molecular docking</title>
      <link>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/projects/acetylcholinesterase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/projects/acetylcholinesterase/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Alzheimer’s disease (AD) is a chronic neurodegenerative disease which leads to the gradual loss of neuronal cells. Several hypotheses for AD exists (e.g., cholinergic, amyloid, tau hypotheses, etc.). As per the cholinergic hypothesis, the deficiency of choline is responsible for AD; therefore, the inhibition of AChE is a lucrative therapeutic strategy for the treatment of AD. Acetylcholinesterase (AChE) is an enzyme that catalyzes the breakdown of the neurotransmitter acetylcholine that is essential for cognition and memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Overview</title>
      <link>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/blog/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/blog/first_post/</guid>
      <description>Regression Problem Different Types of Regressions Example used: Build a model to predict housing prices. Included metrics are population, median income and median housing price.
Multiple Regression: use multiple feature (use district population, the median income) s to make a prediction Additionally
Univariate [[Regression]]: only predict a single value for the output
Multivariate [[Regression]]: predict multiple values per district
Performance Measure Typical Performance measures for regression problems is the Root Mean Square Error</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/about/</guid>
      <description>Background My background is in theoretical condensed matter and quantum physics. I graduated in 2023 from ETH Zurich. I conducted my research in the Materials Theory Group under Prof. Nicola Spaldin. I joined initially in Fall 2022 to work on the behaviour of polar metals, an unusual and even contraindicated combination that leads to some exotic physics.
There as a Student Researcher, I performed electronic structure calculations based on density functional theory and constructed physical Hamiltonian models to demonstrate that two phenomena, the kinetic magnetoelectric effect and the non-linear Hall effect, are universal to polar metals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/blog/bayesian_machine_learning/bayesian_machine_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/blog/bayesian_machine_learning/bayesian_machine_learning/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Rule </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fabianjaeger1.github.io/PersonalWebsite/thoughts/</guid>
      <description>thoughts</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
